<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<thing:thing-descriptions bindingId="zwave"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:thing="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0
                      https://openhab.org/schemas/thing-description/v1.0.0">

  <thing-type id="linear_wadwaz1_00_000" listed="false">
    <label>WADWAZ-1 Door/Windows Sensor</label>
    <description>Door/Windows Sensor&lt;br /&gt&lt;h1&gtOverview&lt;/h1&gt&lt;p&gtLinear Z-Wave products are easy to install, and allow dealers to create an integrated wireless network with nearly limitless expansion and interoperability with security and health monitoring systems, energy management, home entertainment, appliances, and more.&lt;/p&gt &lt;p&gtThe WADWAZ-1 sensor monitors a door or window and sends Z-Wave signals when the door is opened or closed.&lt;/p&gt &lt;br /&gt&lt;h2&gtInclusion Information&lt;/h2&gt&lt;p&gtRefer to your Controller operating instructions to add this module under the command of the Wireless Controller.&lt;/p&gt &lt;ol&gt&lt;li&gtUnscrew the screw fastening the rear cover and slide the rear cover down.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtInsert a CR123A battery into the battery compartment and LED will start to fl ash slowly, which means the sensor has not yet performed “inclusion” with the Controller.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtPrepare the Controller to include a unit to the network by adding it to a group (method of adding a node to the network). Refer to the Controller instructions.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtIf your Controller supports Network Wide Inclusion (NWI) locate the WADWAZ-1 near the proposed installation location. If not skip to Step 6.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtWith your Controller in Inclusion mode, you should see an indication on your Controller that the “device was included” in the network. It should display binary switch / Linear. The LED will stop blinking. Skip to Step 9. If the LED does not stop blinking, relocate the WADWAZ-1 to within 100 feet (line of sight) of a Z-Wave device or your hub and repeat Step 5. If the LED continues to blink, your Controller does not support NWI and continue with Step 6.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtPlace the WADWAZ-1 within 3 feet of the Controller.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtWith your Controller in Inclusion mode, depress the Program switch for 1 second then release.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtYou should see an indication on your Controller that the “device was included” in the network. It should display binary switch / Linear. The LED will stop blinking.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtThe device will appear in the list of Switches&lt;/li&gt &lt;/ol&gt&lt;p&gt&lt;strong&gtNOTE&lt;/strong&gt: If you have trouble adding the WADWAZ-1 to a group it may be that the Home ID and Node ID were not cleared from it after testing. You must first “RESET UNIT” with your Controller to remove it from the network. Although adding it to a group includes it in the network, removing it from a group does not remove it from the network. If removed from a group, it functions as a repeater (only). “RESET UNIT” removes it completely from the network&lt;/p&gt &lt;br /&gt&lt;h2&gtExclusion Information&lt;/h2&gt&lt;p&gtFor “Exclusion” from (removing from) a network:&lt;/p&gt &lt;ol&gt&lt;li&gtSet up the Z-WaveTM Interface Controller into “exclusion” mode, and following its instruction to delete the WADWAZ-1 from the Controller.&lt;/li&gt &lt;li&gtPress the Program switch of WADWAZ-1 for 1 second and release to be excluded. The LED light will fl ash continuously when the sensor is in the Exclusion condition.&lt;/li&gt &lt;/ol&gt&lt;br /&gt&lt;h2&gtWakeup Information&lt;/h2&gt&lt;p&gtOpen and then closed the cover to wakeup the device. This will also trigger the tamper alarm, which needs to be turned off manually.&lt;/p&gt</description>
    <category>Door</category>

    <!-- CHANNEL DEFINITIONS -->
    <channels>
      <channel id="sensor_door" typeId="sensor_door">
        <label>Sensor (Binary)</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OpenClosedType">COMMAND_CLASS_SENSOR_BINARY,COMMAND_CLASS_BASIC</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="alarm_entry" typeId="alarm_entry">
        <label>Sensor (Alarm)</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_ALARM;type=BURGLAR, event=2</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="alarm_tamper" typeId="alarm_tamper">
        <label>Tamper Alarm</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_ALARM;type=BURGLAR, event=3</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="sensor_binary" typeId="sensor_binary">
        <label>Sensor (External Switch)</label>
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:OnOffType">COMMAND_CLASS_ALARM;type=BURGLAR, event=254</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
      <channel id="battery-level" typeId="system.battery-level">
        <properties>
          <property name="binding:*:PercentType">COMMAND_CLASS_BATTERY</property>
        </properties>
      </channel>
    </channels>

    <!-- DEVICE PROPERTY DEFINITIONS -->
    <properties>
      <property name="vendor">Linear Corp</property>
      <property name="modelId">WADWAZ-1</property>
      <property name="manufacturerId">014F</property>
      <property name="manufacturerRef">2001:0102</property>
      <property name="dbReference">9</property>
      <property name="commandClass:COMMAND_CLASS_ALARM">getSupported=false</property>
      <property name="defaultAssociations">1</property>
    </properties>

    <!-- CONFIGURATION DESCRIPTIONS -->
    <config-description>

      <!-- GROUP DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter-group name="association">
        <context>link</context>
        <label>Association Groups</label>
      </parameter-group>

      <!-- ASSOCIATION DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="group_1" type="text" groupName="association" multiple="true">
        <label>1: Controller Updates</label>
        <multipleLimit>5</multipleLimit>
      </parameter>

      <!-- STATIC DEFINITIONS -->
      <parameter name="node_id" type="integer" min="1" max="232" readOnly="true" required="true">
        <label>Node ID</label>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
      </parameter>

    </config-description>

  </thing-type>

</thing:thing-descriptions>
